▍2026 加拿大公开赛（蒙特利尔）1/4 决赛
谢尔顿 6-3 6-1 门西克 · 赛后新闻发布会
for Ben Shelton.
有请谢尔顿
So, Ben,
那么 本
you played an amazing match today.
你今天打了一场了不起的比赛
Can you please give us your thoughts
能不能跟我们说说
on overall what you thought of your game?
你对自己整体状态的看法
Uh, yeah, it was a it was a great night
嗯 对 今晚很棒
for me.
对我来说
Um,
嗯
I think the days like this when everything
我觉得这种一切
is is clicking is a little bit easier.
都对上了的日子会轻松一些
Um, in terms of mentality out on the court,
嗯 说到场上的心态
I think that is a lot tougher on the days
更难的是那种
where you have things
你碰到一些
that you're struggling with or um,
自己很挣扎的事情 或者
problems on your side of the net
自己这边出的问题
that are difficult to solve.
很难解决的那种日子
I think that uh, tonight I was able
我觉得今晚我能
to more dissect more so dissect what
更看清楚
was happening
对面在发生什么
on the other side of the court
在球场那一边
and and find ways to be effective
然后找到应对的办法
and I executed really well tonight.
今晚执行得很好
Hi Ben. Um pretty impressive performance
嗨 本 相当出色的表现
tonight.
今晚
Um overall this week, is it the match
这一整周下来 这是不是
that you're most satisfied of?
你最满意的一场
Uh yeah.
嗯 对
Yeah, I think so.
对 我觉得是的
I think that um the way that I returned,
我觉得我的接发球
the uh the focus that I had from start
还有从头到尾
to finish, how consistent I was able
保持的专注度 我能
to be getting into his service games um
稳定地打进他的发球局
and not getting broken myself.
自己又没被破发
It was my most complete uh performance
这是我这周
so far this week.
目前最完整的一次表现
So yeah,
所以
I'd say it's the the best one this week so far.
这是我这周最好的一场
You said you felt really confident
你说你感觉很自信
and at what point
那是在什么时候
did did that realization sink
意识到
in into that game?
这一场里的
Was it the first break?
是第一个破发点吗
Was it uh right before the game started
还是比赛开始之前
in terms of your sensations?
就有那种感觉了
No, I mean I knew
不 我是说我知道
from uh the first point first or second point
从第一分 或者第二分开始
where we had like a 20 ball rally um
我们打了差不多二十拍的一分
that I was seeing it pretty well.
我看球看得很清楚
Um but obviously I thought that in that first
但显然我觉得那一局
game he played really well too.
他也打得很好
So I thought it was going to be a war,
所以我以为会是一场恶战
a slugfest and um but I I kind
一场硬碰硬 但我
of knew um going in that I was feeling it.
心里知道自己状态在线
Had a great warm up today
今天热身很好
and and and felt u felt like I
感觉自己
was seeing the ball pretty big from from uh
从一开始
the beginning of my warm-up.
热身就看球看得很清楚
Hey Ben, you haven't lost a single uh set
嘿 本 你这周
so far this week.
一盘都没丢过
is what do you feel is working working
你觉得是什么在起作用
for you here in in Canada basically
在加拿大这边
because you won last year.
因为你去年也拿了冠军
So is there there's something
是不是这项赛事
about this tournament that works well
有什么特别
for you?
适合你的地方
I think it's a combination of the court
我觉得是球场
and the balls.
和用球加在一起的原因
Uh it's a slow hard court,
这是慢速的硬地球场
but it bounces really high.
但弹跳很高
Makes my serve really effective,
让我的发球特别有威胁
but also I feel like gives me time to create
同时也给了我时间去创造机会
and and generate um
用底线球
with my ground strokes.
制造压力
I think that, you know, a combination
我觉得这些因素
of all those things makes me difficult
加在一起让我很难对付
to play, especially if I'm returning well
尤其是接发球好的时候
and able to get into, um,
能够打进
the other guys service games.
对手的发球局
So, um, I felt a lot of the same things
我在多伦多也有
in Toronto last year.
很多同样的感觉
I think that the courts play pretty similar,
我觉得那边的场地打感很像
which is great.
这点很棒
And, uh, yeah,
然后
I think it's kind of an accumulation.
我觉得这是一种积累
Um, Jess Pegula's had a lot
嗯 佩古拉在这儿
of success here.
拿了很多成绩
You won last year.
你去年夺冠了
You're in the semis. Are you guys taking
你又进了半决赛 你们是不是
over the country?
要包揽整个国家了
Excuse me.
你说什么
Jess Pegula had a lot of success here.
佩古拉在这儿拿了很多成绩
You won last year also.
你去年也夺冠了
Are you guys taking
你们是不是
over the country like you winning all
要包揽整个国家了 是不是
our tournaments now?
把我们的赛事都拿下了
What was the first name you said?
你刚才说的名字是什么
Jessica Pegula.
杰西卡·佩古拉
Oh, Pegula.
哦 佩古拉
Yeah.
对
Yeah. Uh I wouldn't say that at all.
对 不 我完全不会这么说
Um that's a crazy statement.
这个说法太夸张了
Um super happy for her.
特别为她开心
a good friend and um I think
她是我的好朋友
that she's one of the most dangerous
我觉得她相当难缠
hardcore players 100% year in year out,
硬地球员之一 年年都是
always a contender at the US Open.
美网的争冠热门
Um but yeah, that's a crazy question.
不过 这个问题问得太夸张了
Um Ben, you were talking earlier,
本 你之前说过
I can't remember if it was in DC
我记不清是不是在华盛顿
or not, um just how the early rounds
反正就是说早轮
have felt a little bit trappy for you this year.
今年对你来说感觉有点凶险
How how is the feeling different once you
等你打过几场
have a couple matches under you?
感觉有什么不一样
like does the second week of a major
大满贯第二周
or of a thousand like feel different
或者大师赛后半程
for you now in your mind
现在在你心里
or in your body at all?
或者身体上感觉不一样吗
And then I also wanted to ask you
然后我还想问你
about um Rafael Jodar's game.
霍达尔的球风
I know you haven't played him,
我知道你还没跟他打过
but I wonder if you've watched him
但不知道你有没有看过他打球
and what stands out to you there.
有什么地方让你印象深刻
Uh yeah, first of all, I think
嗯 首先
that um I'm definitely a big match player.
我觉得自己是大场面型选手
I love uh playing big matches, big stadiums,
我喜欢打大赛 大球场
big crowds.
大场面的观众
I like playing against the best guys
我喜欢对阵世界上
in the world.
最好的选手
Uh to be honest, I like going into a match
说实话 我喜欢以
as an underdog.
劣势方的身份进场
Something I enjoy.
我很享受这种感觉
Um I think that, you know,
该怎么说呢
I'm learning better and better how to deal
我是越来越会应对了
with these early Browns or, you know,
这些早轮的凶险局面
dealing with a match coming
怎么面对一场
in as, you know, not a favorite,
自己不是夺冠热门
but uh more or less a top guy with a target
却又背着靶子
on your back, I think is something
的比赛 我觉得这是
that every player has to learn to deal with.
每个球员都得学会应对的事
and um coming out against guys
还要面对那些
who are swinging big, playing free.
放开手脚 大胆挥拍的对手
Um I think that that's something
我觉得这一点
that is is a big piece for me and uh I've
对我来说很重要 而且我
been super impressed with Rafa the way
对拉法这种
that he's come out on tour.
打上巡回赛的方式印象深刻
I I didn't expect there to be another college
我没想到还会有另一个
guy within three years who was 500
大学出身的球员 三年内从世界
in the world and then top 20 within a year.
五百开外 一年内就打进前二十
I mean, he's probably going to be top 10
我是说 他很可能会打进前十
and outdo me uh or or what I did in 2023.
超过我二三年的成绩
I think that he's got a great game,
我觉得他球风很全面
complete game, um, good athlete,
身体素质也好
forehand, backhand, return,
正手 反手 接发球
up there with the best in the world.
都是世界一流水平
Um, I was super entertained
我特别喜欢看
all three times by him
他今年这三次
and Arthur's matchups this year and, uh,
跟菲斯的对决
they're they're hitting the ball incredible
他们的底线击球
from the baseline.
简直难以置信
Um, so I'm I'm super happy for him
所以我特别为他开心
and and yeah, excited to see,
也很期待看到
you know, his trajectory
他接下来的走势
and what he does in the next 18 months.
还有他未来一年半会怎么样
Hi, Ben. Congrats on the win.
嗨 本 祝贺你赢下这场
Uh, if Learner wins tonight,
如果勒纳今晚也赢了
there might be three Americans
半决赛里可能会有
in the in the semi-finals.
三个美国人
Is that something that uh you care
这件事你在意吗
about that you you find cool?
你觉得这很酷吗
And uh do you prefer facing a player
你更愿意面对一个
that you might know
你比较熟悉的对手
a little bit more like him or does it change
还是说这对你来说
at all for you whether you you face
根本没差 不管是打
a player you know pretty well or one
一个很熟的对手
that you might face for the first time?
还是头一次交手的对手
Yeah, I mean obviously uh I've played I
嗯 我肯定
played both of these guys before.
跟这两个人都交过手
Um I've played Learner twice, Merida once.
勒纳打过两次 梅里达打过一次
Um, I'm super uh supportive
我一直都特别支持
of all the American players at all times
所有的美国球员
and I've really enjoyed being able
我也真心很享受
to see how many guys
能看到这么多人
that we've had have success.
都打出了成绩
Um, you know, it's not just been one or two,
不只是一两个人
but we've kind of spread the wealth around.
而是大家都在开花结果
um between Taylor, Foe, Tommy, Sebi,
弗里茨 蒂亚福 保罗 科达
uh Nakashima, Learner, Nicholson,
中岛布兰登 勒纳 尼科尔森
so many guys who've made deep runs.
这么多人都打出了深轮
And I think that it's just really cool
我觉得这真的很酷
to see the direction that that our country
能看到我们国家的网球
is going in terms of tennis.
正朝着这个方向发展
Um I think we got a lot of young guys,
我觉得我们还有很多年轻人
too, with a lot of potential
潜力都很大
that people don't really know yet.
只是大家还不太了解
But, um I'll be super excited
但我会特别期待
to play either one of these guys.
跟他们俩当中的任何一个交手
Young guys playing great tennis.
年轻人打得很棒
Uh Merida just got his first title I think
梅里达好像刚拿到首个冠军
and yeah learn learner over the last year
勒纳过去这一年
and a half has established himself
半里已经证明了自己
as you know one of one of the best players
是最厉害的球员之一
and one of the best baseliners on tour.
也是巡回赛顶尖的底线型选手
So two completely different matchups
所以是两种完全不同的对决
but be looking forward to either one
但不管是哪一场我都很期待
of them.
两个我都期待
Last question.
最后一个问题
You said you you prefer
你说过你更喜欢
to be the um not overlooked
做那种不被高估
the underrated player of the underdog.
被低估的劣势方
Uh but you wrote on the lens not done yet.
但你在镜头上写了 还没结束
What's the What's the goal in Montreal?
你在蒙特利尔的目标是什么
And do you feel at this point
到了这个阶段
where the semi-finals come
半决赛都打到了
in that you've got the target on your back?
你还觉得自己背着靶子吗
Uh I I don't think I'm really looking at it
我其实不这么看
at all from that perspective.
自己是从这个角度去想的
I think that there's
应该说
so much more to gain uh being here.
站在这里还能拿到更多东西
Obviously,
很明显
I think that my tennis has gotten better
我觉得我的球越打越好
and better with each match that I've played.
每打一场都在进步
And um that's the coolest thing
这就是最棒的地方
about these events is you
在这种赛事里
have the opportunity, the runway
你有机会 有空间
to continue to to build on your game
去继续打磨自己的技术
and improve uh night in night out.
一场一场地进步
So to to be back here tomorrow, have some
所以明天还要再回到这儿
continuity now playing back-to-back days,
接着打 保持这种连续性
I think is is great for for my level um
我觉得对我的水平
for my game and and yeah,
对我的球风都很好
just looking forward to to try
就是很期待
to improve tomorrow.
明天能再进步一点